友人一:嗨,开萝尔.
Friend 1: Hi Carol!
开萝尔:嗨!
Carol: Hi.
友人二:跟我们一块去看篮球队训练好吗?
Friend 2: Wanna come with us to watch the basketball team workout?
开萝尔:那有什么好看的.
Carol: Why would I want to do that?
友人一:去看那个穿短裤衩的高个子.
Friend 1: Tall, tall guys in teeny-weeny shorts?
友人二:还有特大号的臀部,你懂我的意思吗?
Friend 2: Gluteus to the maximus, if you get my meaning.
Carol: Uh, sorry, I can't.I'm helping Bobby study for an English test
友人一:哦!真的吗?
Friend 1 and 2: Whoop-de-do.
友人二:开萝尔你跟鲍比刚好上,
Friend 2: Carol, when you and Bobby started going out we had great hope
我们就对你们充满信心.
for you.
友人一:充满信心.
Friend 1: Great hope!
友人二:可是你们俩的关系怎么变得不冷不热的了?
Friend 2: But your relationship has turned into something disgustingly boring.
开萝尔:不冷不热,
Carol: Boring, huh?Well,
因为我们不像时髦青年那样,
just because we don't run around here like teenagers,
四面八方去兜风,难道非得像他们那样,
doesn't mean that underneath there's not a seething river of white,
才能算是有挚热的感情.
hot passion.
鲍比:哦开萝尔,我来晚了,
Bobby: Yo, Carol!Look, I'm sorry I'm late, but I can't study right now.
现在我不能温课,我得去参加训练,
I owe Coach Lump some power squats.
训练一完我就去你家,好
But I'll study at your house after football practice, ok?
开萝尔:可以.
Carol: Sure.
鲍比:吻你.
Bobby: Kiss!
开萝尔:很好.
Carol: Kiss!
友人一:他有没有感到厌烦.
Friend 1: Is that sick or what?
友人二:开萝尔,承认吧,
Friend 2: Carol, admit it.
爱情的热流就像我母亲的皮肤一样干.
The river of passion has dried up like my mother's skin.
开萝尔:现在看来,
Carol: Well, it's obvious that neither one of you have ever been involved
显然你们俩谁都没有尝到那种深沉持久的爱情.
in a mature, lasting relationship.
友人一:没人稀罕.
Friend 1: Who'd want to be?
开萝尔:所以你们怎么能够理解鲍比和我的想法,
Carol: So how could you possibly understand that Bobby and I are different?
我们绝不是光品尝时髦青年那种奔放的恋情,
We're not into that typical flirty, giggling kind of teenage fling.
而是在建立持久美好的爱情,即使白马王子向我走来,
We're building something lasting and good.And even if Mr.
我也会说我有意中人了.
Perfect were to walk up to me right now, I'd say, I'm taken.'
杰弗瑞:哦!对不起.
Jeffrey: Oh, excuse me.
开萝尔:不,是我不好.
Carol: No, it's my fault.
杰弗瑞:请问生物实验室在哪?我刚来这儿.
Jeffrey: Could you tell me where the biology lab is?I'm new.
开萝尔:我带你去!
Carol: I'm taken.
杰弗瑞:我出生在萨利纳,而且是一直生活在那儿,
Jeffrey: Not only was I born in Salinas, but I lived there all my life.
有一天爸爸对我们说要搬家了,我们都愣了.
So when my dad announced that we were moving, it was quite a shock.
开萝尔:是这样的.
Carol: I'll bet.
杰弗瑞:变化是好事,
Jeffrey: Change is good, right?
因为谁也不愿意每天过老一套的生活.
I mean, who wants life to be the same, day after day after day?
开萝尔:
Carol: Not me.
杰弗瑞:新的环境,新的探索.
Jeffrey: New places, new adventures.
开萝尔:新面孔.
Carol: New people.
杰弗瑞:对,还有意想不到的事.
Jeffrey: Yea, chance at the unexpected.
开萝尔:是啊,哦对了,我到家了.
Carol: Yea.Yea, well, this is my house.
杰弗瑞:别逗了,我家离这儿才两条街.
Jeffrey: No kidding!I'm just down the road a couple of blocks!
开萝尔:真的.
Carol: Really?
杰弗瑞:是缘分.
Jeffrey: It's gotta be fate.
开萝尔:我想是的.
Carol: Must be.
杰弗瑞:也许我们能一起走着去上学.
Jeffrey: So, uh, maybe we can walk to school together sometimes?
开萝尔:平时我乘公共汽车,有时我哥哥带我,
Carol: Well, uh, I usually ride the bus or my brother takes me.
我们一起走着去.
We could do that.
杰弗瑞:这是我来新学校的好兆头,
Jeffrey: You know, this has been a pretty good first day at my new school.
我的声音就像无事生非里的詹姆斯·迪安.
Geez, I sound like James Dean in Rebel Without A Cause.
开萝尔:他遇见了娜塔莉亚·伍德.
Carol: Where he met Natalie Wood!
杰弗瑞:对!
Jeffrey: Yea!
开萝尔:对!
Carol: Yea!
杰弗瑞:娜塔莉亚对他并没有好感.
Jeffrey: Only she wasn't as nice to him as you've been to me.
开萝尔:哦,没办法,
Carol: Well, how could she be?I mean, she was going steady with Buzz.
因为他对巴兹太专一.那时候他一点也不知道詹姆斯·迪安,
At that point in the movie she had no idea that,
命中注定会成为自己的情人,成为他可怜的玩物.
that James Dean was fated to be her soul mate, her Boy, was Natalie a dunce.
杰森:本你在干什么?
Jason: Ben, what are you doing?
本:我在看开萝尔交上了新的男朋友.
Ben: Watching Carol flirt with some guy and he's not Bobby.
杰森:这不关你的事,是谁?
Jason: Well, that's not of your bus What guy?
本:不认识,但我想他是个傻瓜.
Ben: I don't know, but I think he's a little weird.
杰森:为什么?
Jason: Why?
本:他对开萝尔感兴趣.
Ben: He's interested in Carol.
杰森:还要我教你离远点吗?
Jason: Didn't I tell you to stay away from that window?
你姐姐可不是那种非常下贱姑娘.
Besides, your sister is not the type who flirts.
本:我看有点,得告诉鲍比.
Ben: They all are, Dad.Wait till I tell Bobby.
杰森:本……
Jason: Ben.
本:好,好,好.
Ben: Yea, yea, yea.
杰弗瑞:我还要去图书馆,我得走了.
Jeffrey: Well, if I'm gonna get to the library, I better get going.
开萝尔:好,我也得走了,事多着呢.
Carol: Yea.I gotta go, too.Lots to do.
杰弗瑞:谢谢开萝尔.遇上了你,
Jeffrey: Thanks, Carol.And for what it's worth,
我感到特别高兴.
I'm really glad I bumped into you today.
迈克:吆!开萝尔.
Mike: Yo, Carol!
开萝尔:鲍比,迈克你在跟踪我?
Carol: Bobby!Mike, you were spying on me!
迈克:不,
Mike: Me?Oh, no, no, Carol.
不,那家伙的话我一个字也没听见,
I didn't hear a word the guy said including, And for what it's worth,
什么遇上了你我感到特别的高兴.
I'm really glad I bumped into you today.'
开萝尔:你这种行为,难道你不感到太低级,太庸俗了吗?
Carol: You are so gross.You are so indescribably low.
迈克:哦,
Mike: Oh?Oh, maybe,
你怎么不说有人同时谈两个男朋友是庸俗呢?
would you say as low as somebody who would two-time their boyfriend?
开萝尔:我只是向一个新来的同学,伸出了友谊之手,
Carol: Just because I extend my hand in friendship to a new student on
这一点并不能表明我,
his first day of school is no reason to think that I'm, I'm,
我,我就对他感兴趣.
I'm interested in him.
迈克:鲍比知道你说谎时会口吃吗?
Mike: So, does Bobby know you stutter when you lie?
开萝尔:我,我不口吃.
Carol: I do not!
麦琪:开萝尔你没把鲍比忘了吧?
Maggie: Carol, honey, are you forgetting about Bobby?
开萝尔:我没忘掉鲍比,我们相处的很好,
Carol: I am not forgetting about Bobby.I was just being friendly.
这跟你有什么关系?
What is with you people?
麦琪:哦开萝尔,
Maggie: Carol, honey, I just meant Bobby's waiting downstairs to study
我是说鲍比正在楼下等你温课呢.
with you.
开萝尔:哦,是的.
Carol: Oh, yea.
麦琪:Carol怎么回事?
Maggie: Carol, is everything ok?
开萝尔:妈妈你相信命运吗?
Carol: Mom, do you believe in fate?
麦琪:命运?
Maggie: Fate?
开萝尔:是的,是这样的,
Carol: Well, you know,
有一种无情的力量,
that there are these inexorable forces that can push us towards certain
在左右着我们,对他我们又无法抗拒.
things and we're powerless to stop them?
麦琪:左右什么?
Maggie: What, uh, things?
开萝尔:我打个比方吧妈妈,好吧,
Carol: Uh, let me put this another way, Mom.Ok, alright, alright.
对了,对了,
Let's say you're out for a walk, ok?And you pass a shoe store, ok?
比方说你外出散步你走过一家鞋店,是的,
And we'll say the mall.
你欣赏橱窗的鞋子,你发现有一双鞋特别的好看,
Now in this shoe store you see this really hot looking pair of shoes.
而事实上你不需要新鞋,
Now you really don't need new shoes, I mean,
我是说你的旧鞋挺合脚,你甚至没有打算要买新鞋,
your old ones are very comfortable and fine and you wouldn't have even
只是偶尔路过这个鞋店,而那双新鞋,
thought about getting a new pair except that fate brought you to this store,
它看上去那么漂亮时髦,而又是那么的吸引人,
with this window, and these shoes standing right there looking so sexy
你该怎么办,妈妈?
and right.Uh, what would you do, Mom?
麦琪:哦,鞋子是什么颜色?
Maggie: What color are these shoes?
开萝尔:颜色倒无关紧要.
Carol: Mom, color doesn't matter.
麦琪:颜色当然重要,
Maggie: Well, of course the color matters.
因为要和衣服颜色相配.
If you have to buy a new dress to go with them, it's...
开萝尔:妈妈,妈妈,颜色很中意,试样好,颜色很相配.
Carol: Mom!Mom!They're the right color, the perfect color and style.
麦琪:好吧,价格是否优惠?
Maggie: Ok, are they on sale?
开萝尔:算了,不说了妈妈.
Carol: Never mind, Mom.
友人一:他又在捏手指了,真是粗俗.
Friend 1: He's cracking his knuckles again.How gross.
友人二:没什么,
Friend 2: So what?This is what building a mature,
他们的爱情是建立在深沉和持久的基础上的.
long lasting relationship is all about.
友人一:哦,我忘了,
Friend 1: Oh, yea, I forgot.
也许他们在一起过上二三十年以后开萝尔会习惯的.
Well, Carol will probably get used to it after they've
been together for about twenty or thirty years
开萝尔:请你别捏了好吗?
Carol: Would you stop that please?
鲍比:什么?
Bobby: What?
开萝尔:别再捏手指了.
Carol: Cracking your knuckles.
鲍比:哦,我不是故意的.
Bobby: Oh, I didn't even know I was doing it.
友人二:你看他的小毛病还挺多.
Friend 2: Ok, he's not perfect.
友人一:他比不上詹姆斯·迪安
Friend 1: He's no James Dean.
友人二:问题不仅仅在于这些讨厌的坏习惯,
Friend 2: What matters here isn't a few annoying little habits like cracking
比如捏手指,挠痒和吸鼻子,
his knuckles, breathing through his nose, scratching himself,
关键还有一些非常不拘小节的习惯.
hit and miss personal hygiene.
友人一:比如足球训练以后他不洗澡.
Friend 1: Don't they shower after football practice?
友人二:也不能光看表面现象,
Friend 2: What matters is what's beneath the surface.
鲍比是个有学问有见识的人.
Bobby here is someone intelligent you can talk to.
鲍比:我一点也不想看这本红字了,
Bobby: You know, I don't get this Scarlet Letter garbage at all.
我要是斯佳丽·赖特我就把红A字塞进那些伪君子的嘴里.
I mean, if I was this Hester chick,
那个叫豪斯恩的作家,是个十足的阴阳人,
I'd rip off the A and stuff it in the mouth of any guy who got
你说呢?
smart.Boy, this Nate Hawthorne guy is a major ying yang, you know what I mean?
开萝尔:呃,嗯!没错!
Carol: Uh, yea, yea.Yes I do.
友人二:我在想那个帅哥现在做什么呢?
Friend 2:I wonder what that cute transfer student is doing right now?
友人一:你是说詹姆斯·迪安
Friend: 1: You mean James Dean?
友人二:不是,他叫杰弗瑞.
Friend 2: No, his name is Jeffrey.
鲍比:嘿!明晚我们去看电影怎么样?
Bobby: Hey, what do you say we got to a movie tomorrow night?
友人二:别提那个杰弗瑞了,或许这小子不错,
Friend 2: Forget Jeff.He may be perfect but Carol's already taken by a
但他钟情开萝尔,而且已经取得她的绝对信任和依赖.
guy who's completely reliable and predictable.
鲍比:开萝尔?
Bobby: Carol?
开萝尔:噢!你到底想说什么?
Carol: Oh, uh, what word don't you know?
鲍比:不是,我想请你去看场电影.
Bobby: No, I wanted to know if you wanted to go to a movie tomorrow night.
开萝尔:除了周末,我们从不在晚上看电影.
Carol: Well, gee, we never go to the movies on weeknights.
鲍比:这种古板的规定,
Bobby: So?Do we have to do the same thing day after day, day in,
难道就不能灵活的改变一下.
day out?
开萝尔:不行!
Carol: No.
鲍比:我们去疯一下.
Bobby: So, let's get crazy!
开萝尔:那么好,对,
Carol: Well, ok, yea!You know, you know, maybe we could rent something.
也许,也许我们的爱好不同,不过我非常想看詹姆斯·迪安的影片.
I'm really in the mood to see a James Dean movie.
鲍比:詹姆斯·迪安!我也喜欢.
Bobby: James Dean!I like him!
开萝尔:哦,真的.
Carol: Oh, you do?
鲍比:绝不会假,另外他做香肠也是挺在行的.
Bobby: Heck, yea!So he acts when he's not cranking out sausages, huh?
杰弗瑞:开萝尔!
Jeffrey: Carol!
开萝尔:鲍比!你去哪了?哦,嗨.
Carol: Bobby!Where have you Oh, hi.
杰弗瑞:说出来你不信,
Jeffrey: You are not gonna believe this.
昨天我去图书馆,路过新开的剧院,
On my way to the library yesterday,
你猜再在演什么?
I passed that revival movie theatre and guess what was playing?
开萝尔:演什么?
Carol: What?
杰弗瑞:在演无事生非.
Jeffrey: Rebel Without A Cause.
开萝尔:是真的.
Carol: No!
杰弗瑞:对,太诱人了.
Jeffrey: Yea, isn't that incredible?
开萝尔:命运安排的.
Carol: Must be fate.
杰弗瑞:也许今晚你也想去看.
Jeffrey: So I was thinking, maybe we could go tonight.
开萝尔:跟你一起去.哇!我不能,要我一起去?
Carol: Go out with you?Well, I really don't.Go out with you, huh?
友人二:开萝尔这是命运安排的.
Friend 2: Carol, you said it.It's fate!
友人一:你就别命运了.
Friend 1: Don't try to fight it.
友人二:去他的Bobby,去吧.
Friend 2: Dust Bobby!Go for it!
Friend 1 and 2: 鲍比for it!Go for it!Go for it!
友人一:去吧,去吧,去吧.
开萝尔:去吧.
Carol: Go for it!
杰弗瑞:7点钟我来接你.
Jeffrey: Pick you up at seven.
鲍比:开萝尔,对不起.
Bobby: Yo, Carol!Sorry!
开萝尔:鲍比你去哪了?你早就该来了.
Carol: Bobby!Where have you been?I didn't think you were coming.
鲍比:你该了解我是老迟到的.
Bobby: Well, you know me, Carol.I'm always late.
开萝尔:我猜对了.
Carol: Exactly.
鲍比:你猜对什么了?
Bobby: Well, what is that supposed to mean?
开萝尔:你别大声嚷嚷.
Carol: There's no reason to yell.
鲍比:我没嚷嚷.
Bobby: I'm not yelling.
开萝尔:你再这样下去,
Carol: If you're going to carry on this way,
只能使我们俩都不自在.
it's only going to embarrass us both.
开萝尔:嗯?
Bobby: Huh?
开萝尔:我是说你总是这么冷淡我,原因只有一个.
Carol: If you can be so inconsiderate of me, it can only mean one thing.
鲍比:什么原因?
Bobby: What's that?
开萝尔:你厌倦我了.
Carol: You're tired of me.
鲍比:我厌倦你.
Bobby: I'm tired of you?
开萝尔:你就不用否认了.
Carol: Oh, so you don't deny it!
鲍比:我否认什么?
Bobby: Deny what?
开萝尔:下一步你肯定要跟我一刀两断.
Carol: I suppose next you're going to say you want to break up with me.
鲍比:等一等,你现在怎么突然变成这样了.
Bobby: Wait a minute here.What's going on?Why you acting like this?
开萝尔:别像对小孩子那样来指责我.
Carol: Oh, so childish to blame me.
鲍比:肯定有原因,你另有男朋友了?
Bobby: Oh, there's something going on.You got another guy or what?
开萝尔:哦,你不弄点麻烦出来,你是不会痛快的,对吗?
Carol: Oh.You have to drag this into the gutter don't you?
鲍比:什么麻烦?
Bobby: Drag what?
开萝尔:也许我想多了,你是想断绝我俩的关系.
Carol: I suppose next you're going to say you want to break up with me, huh?
鲍比:我从来没有想过.
Bobby: I don't want to break up with you.
开萝尔:我和你一样,可是,
Carol: Well, neither do I!
可是,
But, but under the circumstances I do think it would be a good idea for
既然是这样,我想我们俩现在还是暂时分开一段时间比较好.
both of us to see a little less of each other.
鲍比:好吧,既然你是这么想的,那我们就分手吧.
Bobby: Ok, ok, fine.If that's the way you want it.We'll break up!Fine!
开萝尔:好吧,你别忘了分手两个字可是你说的.
Carol: Fine!But just remember, breaking up was your idea!
友人二:开萝尔!
Friend 2: Carol!
友人一:你和鲍比这是怎么了?
Friend 1: What is going on with you and Bobby?
开萝尔:好像你们不知道一样.
Carol: As if you didn't know.
麦琪:我不是说你对Carol不关心.
Maggie: I did not say you were insensitive to Carol.
杰森:哦,
Jason: Oh, no, no, no.
不不你说了,你不能对我们的伤心的女儿,
You said, Honey, couldn't you muster a little sympathy for our heartbroken
多一点同情心吗?
daughter?
麦琪:是的,那是在事情发生之后.
Maggie: Yes, after what this jock did to her.
杰森:她没说男朋友抛弃了她,她说她们分手了.
Jason: Honey, she didn't say that he dumped her.She said they broke up.
麦琪:你相信她说的了?
Maggie: And you believed her.
杰森:你明白我说的意思,
Jason: You know what I think?
你只不过是被夸大的事实搞昏了头.
I think that you're just getting swept up in all the melodrama.
麦琪:夸大的事实,杰森你知道我们天真的女儿,
Maggie: Melodrama?Jason, our innocent little girl takes one tentative
她才刚刚涉足爱河,可受到的打击竟会这么沉重.
step into the tumultuous world of dating only to have it chopped off!
杰森:我认为事情没有那么严重.
Jason: I really don't think Carol has lost a limb.
麦琪:好吧,我现在可以说你确实无动于衷.
Maggie: Ok, this time I will say it.You are insensitive.
杰森:对不起,我没听开萝尔说,要同她的男朋友分手.
Jason: Well, I'm sorry.I didn't notice Carol was all that broken up.
麦琪:那是她隐瞒了杰森,因为你还不理解女人.
Maggie: She was covering.Jason don't you know anything about women?
杰森:不.
Jason: No.
麦琪:鲍比是她第一个男朋友,也是她第一个恋人.
Maggie: Bobby was her first boyfriend, her first real love.
杰森:我知道.
Jason: I know.
麦琪:你知道什么?
Maggie: You know what I think?
开萝尔说他们分手了,其实她是在撒谎,
I think when Carol told us they broke up she was lying.
是鲍比抛弃了她.
I think Bobby dumped her.
杰森:你肯定?
Jason: You do?
麦琪:这下你高兴了吧.
Maggie: And you're happy about it.
杰森:高兴,你说我高兴.
Jason: Honey, do I look happy?
麦琪:杰森你平时总是说,
Maggie: Jason, how many times have you said that Carol should not be going
开萝尔不应该只跟她第一个男朋友保持关系.
steady with the first guy she ever dated?
杰森:你也同意我的观点.
Jason: And you agreed with me.
麦琪:我当然同意了.
Maggie: Of course I did.
杰森:那他们俩分手不是件好事吗?
Jason: Well, then, you think it's good that they're not together?
麦琪:不行!
Maggie: No!
杰森:你情愿让开萝尔只和鲍比呆在一起,
Jason: Oh, so you prefer that Carol and Bobby were together for the rest
也不让她接触任何人,这样的话还有什么机会,
of their lives so Carol wouldn't meet any other guys and she'd never have
让她开阔眼界.
a chance to broaden her horizons?
麦琪:哦,我当然不是这样的.
Maggie: Oh, of course not!
杰森:麦琪你把我弄得越来越糊涂了.
Jason: Maggie, I'm getting very confused with this conversation.
麦琪:这是很清楚的事.
Maggie: Well, obviously!
杰森:也许是我无动于衷,她脑子坏了.
Jason: Well, maybe I am insensitive!Maybe she's nuts!
开萝尔:进来.
Carol: Come in.
麦琪:亲爱的,我知道你现在很痛苦,我也是个女人.
Maggie: Honey, I know exactly what you're feeling.I'm a woman, too.
开萝尔:这我知道.
Carol: I know that.
麦琪:你听着,痛苦会过去,
Maggie: All I can say is the hurt will fade with each passing day it'll
过一段时间你很快就会把他忘记的.
easier and easier to forget him.
开萝尔:谁?
Carol: Who?
麦琪:鲍比!
Maggie: Bobby.
开萝尔:哦,对.
Carol: Oh, yea.
麦琪:宝贝我告诉你一件事,是关于我和第一个恋人的事,
Maggie: Honey, I want to tell you a story about my first love and how
那时候他太伤我的心了,可后来……
he broke my heart and I ended up stronger for...
开萝尔:妈妈故事长吗?
Carol: Mom, is this a long story?
麦琪:不,不,不.
Maggie: No, no, not really.
开萝尔:我有约会.
Carol: Cause I have a date.
麦琪:很好,你应该想到你还有许多别的男朋友.
Maggie: Good because it's important for you to realize there are so many
什么,你有约会?
other boys out there and you have a date?
杰森:我想你是对的,我应该让开萝尔知道,
Jason: Hey, I decided you were right.
我也为她伤心.
I should let Carol know that I hurt for her, too.
麦琪:为什么?
Maggie: Why?
杰森:你说什么来着?
Jason: Pardon me?
麦琪:她不需要你去安慰,她有约会.
Maggie: She doesn't need you to cheer her up.She's got a date!
杰森:哦,是跟鲍比?
Jason: Oh, with Bobby?
麦琪:当然不是,她抛弃了Bobby.
Maggie: Of course not!She dumped Bobby!
杰森:是鲍比抛弃了她.
Jason: I thought Bobby dumped her.
麦琪:杰森,你说我还得再碰几次壁.
Maggie: Jason, how many times do I have to go over this?
杰森:再碰一次,就一次.
Jason: Oh, just one more.
娜塔莉亚·伍德:她看上去,究竟是爱上了哪一位?
Natalie Wood: Is this what's it like to love somebody?
詹姆斯·迪安:我不知道.
James Dean: I don't know.
娜塔莉亚·伍德:你认为姑娘会爱上什么样的人?
Natalie Wood: What kind of a person do you think a girl wants?
詹姆斯·迪安:一个男人.
James Dean: A man.
娜塔莉亚·伍德:是的,但他应该是温和的,充满爱心的人,就像你.
Natalie Wood: Yes, but a man who can be gentle and sweet, like you are.
开萝尔:哦,我真喜欢这部片子.
Carol: Oh, gosh, do I love this movie.
杰弗瑞:特别是跟你一起看.
Jeffrey: It's even better seeing it with you.
开萝尔:谢谢.杰弗瑞!杰弗瑞!杰弗瑞!咱们还是好好看电影好吗?
Carol: Thanks.Jeff, Jeff, Jeff.We should watch the movie.Ok?
杰弗瑞:好的,好的.
Jeffrey: Alright.
开萝尔:不杰弗瑞,我是说正经的.
Carol: No, Jeff.I'm serious.
杰弗瑞:你怎么了?
Jeffrey: What's with you?
开萝尔:你指什么?
Carol: What do you mean?
杰弗瑞:你喜欢我,
Jeffrey: I know you like me.
否则你不会抛弃男朋友的.
You wouldn't have dumped your boyfriend if you didn't.
开萝尔:我没真的抛弃他,你怎么知道我和鲍比的事?
Carol: I didn't dump Wait, how did you know I was going with Bobby?
杰弗瑞:说不清楚,学校里都在传.
Jeffrey: I don't know.Heard it around school.
开萝尔:就是说你约我以前就知道了.
Carol: So you knew that when you asked me out?
杰弗瑞:是的.
Jeffrey: Sure.
开萝尔:你为什么不对我说.
Carol: Why didn't you say something?
杰弗瑞:你没拒绝.
Jeffrey: Why didn't you?
开萝尔:我不知道.
Carol: I don't know.
杰弗瑞:听着,
Jeffrey: See?You didn't want that to stand in our way anymore than I did.
你比我更不想让那种关系来妨碍我们,在我决定和你巧遇时,
I knew exactly what I wanted from the moment I decided to bump into you
我非常清楚我想得到什么.
at your locker.
开萝尔:真的?但是我以为是命运把我们安排在一起的.
Carol: Really?But I thought it was fate that brought us together.
杰弗瑞:哦,是的.
Jeffrey: It was.
开萝尔:那次巧遇,你说是你事先安排的?
Carol: But, you just said you planned our meeting.
杰弗瑞:不错,
Jeffrey: Ok, I did plan it.
是我安排的,一个男人想和最善交际的姑娘好的话,
A guy cannot depend on mere fate when he's trying to meet the most popular
单靠缘分是绝不行的.
girl in school.
开萝尔:什么?你怎么会那么看我呢?
Carol: What?What makes you think that I'm that?
杰弗瑞:跟足球队长在一起的姑娘,
Jeffrey: The girl who goes with the captain of the football team is always
总是学校里的交际花.
the most popular girl in school.
开萝尔:可我不是学校里的什么交际花,我不是的,
Carol: But I'm not the most popular girl in school, not even close!
根本不是的.
That's not me at all!
杰弗瑞:嘘,别激动.
Jeffrey: Why are you getting so excited?
开萝尔:我也不知道.
Carol: I'm not sure.
我想的和现实完全是两回事.
This just isn't exactly what I thought it would be like at all.
杰弗瑞:你想什么了?
Jeffrey: Well, what did you expect?
开萝尔:我想的,我想的就像电影里的一样,
Carol: Something, something like up on that screen.Something meant to be.
我在想也许这就是缘分,我以为你的突然出现是偶然的,
Something destined.See, I thought that you came out of the blue and that
你说得很对,
you were so right.
我们的相见并不是意外的,而像是命运安排的.
And it was not just some accident that we met but that it was fate.
但实际上,你是把我当成了交交际花才和我约会的.
But it wasn't.You were just scheming because you thought that I was popular.
杰弗瑞:嗨,行了,
Jeffrey: Hey, come on!Look, we're here together at a great movie.
你看我们不是坐在一起看电影了吗?这是我们事先安排好的,
So we both schemed a little bit to get here.So what?
实际上我比那个叫什么来着的,更贴心.
What matters is that I'm a lot better for you than what's his name.
开萝尔:他叫鲍比,即使我不满意他,他也比你强.
Carol: His name is Bobby and he doesn't flinch when I do that to him.
在旁观众:嘘-嘘-嘘.
Audience: Shhh!
开萝尔:滚一边去.
Carol: Shh, yourselves!
麦琪:好了,她回来了,我来跟她谈.
Maggie: Ok, here she comes.You want to talk to her?
杰森:我看还是我们俩一起来谈吧.
Jason: Well, I think both of us would be a bit much.
麦琪:好吧,听你的.
Maggie: Right.You handle it.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:嗨.杰森.
Maggie: Hello!Jason!
杰森:对了开萝尔,我们俩很想听听你和鲍比最近的关系?
Jason: Yes, well, Carol,
I think that we should have a little talk about this whole situation with
Bobby.
开萝尔:鲍比?我跟鲍比的关系,
Carol: Bobby?The situation with Bobby?I blew it!
我们吹了,开萝尔·西维尔一个被认为漂亮聪明的姑娘,
Carol Seaver the girl who's supposed to be so smart,
就因为不十分满意她的男朋友,所以最终还是失去了他,我自私,
just lost the only guy she's ever cared about because she treated him
我也渺小,这就是我跟鲍比最近的关系.
like dirt!I was mean and I was selfish.That's the situation with Bobby.
杰森:宝贝,我没有.
Jason: Aw, honey, I didn't
麦琪:杰森我没说要吓唬她.
Maggie: Jason, I didn't say to browbeat her.
鲍比:开萝尔,你在……
Bobby: Carol, what're you...
开萝尔:鲍比亲爱的,请听我说几句,
Carol: Bobby, honey, before you say anything.
我要为我昨天对你的刻薄行为向你道歉,我真是太……
I just want to apologize for my obnoxious behavior yesterday.I am so...
友人一:嗨开萝尔.
Friend 1: Hi, Carol.
开萝尔:嗨,什么?
Carol: Hi.What?
鲍比:开萝尔,你的判断没错,是该另找个人了.
Bobby: Carol, you were absolutely right about seeing other people.
友人一:我们去上课吧,亲爱的.
Friend 1: We better get to class, Bobby, honey.
鲍比:她不会让我迟到的.
Bobby: She won't let me be late.
开萝尔:这是不可能的.
Carol: This is not happening.
杰森:不,不,是的本,事实上连我也不明白女人,哦.
Jason: No, no.Truth is, Ben, even I don't understand women.
开萝尔:爸爸我要感谢你对我的宽容,而且我犯了那么大的错误,
Carol: Dad, I would like to thank you for allowing me to blunder my way
它差不多把我的一生都给毁了.
into an even bigger mistake that's virtually ruined my entire life.
杰森:怎么回事?
Jason: What happened?
开萝尔:我对鲍比毕竟是认真的,
Carol: After all that Bobby and I have meant to each other he dumps me
可他扔下我去找那个冒出来的黛比,他对黛比又不了解,
for that airhead Debbie, a girl that he hardly even knows, Dad.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe that?
杰森:你自己对鲍比又是怎么样的呢?
Jason: Well, you know...
本:这不也恰恰是你对待鲍比的方式吗?
Ben: Isn't that exactly what you did to Bobby?
杰森:本说到点子上了.
Jason: I think maybe Ben has a point.
开萝尔:是吗?
Carol: You do?
本:这是毫无疑问的.
Ben: Yup, he do.
鲍比:肯定她不在.
Bobby: You sure she's not home?
迈克:是的.如果她在,
Mike: Yea, yea, look, if she was, she'd be sitting there on the couch,
她一定是坐在长沙发上,傻乎乎的做作业.让我感到沮丧.
doing her stupid homework, making me look bad.
鲍比:我只想赶紧取回东西就走.
Bobby: Look, Mike.I just want to get my stuff and get out of here.
迈克:快来.我知道她抽屉里放的什么.
Mike: Yea, come on.I know which drawer she keeps everything in.
Bobby: No, I no longer have the right to go near Carol's drawers
开萝尔:你来这儿干吗?
Carol: What're you doing here?
鲍比:我以为你下午去下棋了.
Bobby: I thought you had chess club this afternoon.
迈克:哦,好了,
Mike: Oh, well, right.I'll leave you two alone.
我现在该撤了,你们俩肯定有很多话要讲.
I'm sure you two got lots to talk about.
开萝尔:我没有什么话好说的.
Carol: Well, I don't have anything to talk about.
鲍比:我也是的.我一会儿来取得我的遥控坦克.
Bobby: Neither do I.I'll come back later for my Tony Danza tank top.
开萝尔:向黛比问好啊!
Carol: Say hi to Debbie!
鲍比:要知道,是你先跟别人出去约会的,我找黛比,是因为你找了那个Va-va-va-voom.
Bobby: You know, you're the one who went out with other people in the first place.I only went out with Debbie cause you went out with Mr.Va-va-va-voom!
开萝尔:我和别人在一起又有什么错,我们又不是夫妻,
Carol: Well, what's wrong with going out with other people?
难道你不知道.
We weren't officially going steady remember?
鲍比:你说对了,
Bobby: You're right.It wasn't official.
不是夫妻,所以我也约黛比了,
So that's why I'm going out with Debbie.
你有什么理由可以发火的开萝尔.
And you got no reason to be mad, Carol!
开萝尔:你讲的,你,你是对的.
Carol: Well, yea?Well, you're right.
鲍比:凡是鹅可以玩的游戏,耗子照样也可以玩,
Bobby: And what's good for the goose is good for the mice to play when
只要猫不在场.
the cat's away.
开萝尔:你说得对.
Carol: You're right.
鲍比:我也是这么做的.
Bobby: And I'm right!I'm right?
开萝尔:是的,听着,
Carol: Yes.Look, I never should have gone out with Jeff.
我不应该跟杰弗瑞出去,
It was the worst mistake I have ever made.
我犯的这个错误是最最糟糕的,你完全有理由来怨恨我.
And you have every right to hate me.
鲍比:不开萝尔,我做不到.
Bobby: No, Carol.I couldn't hate you.
开萝尔:能做到,很简单,我是自食其果.
Carol: Sure you can.It's easy.I'm a slime bucket.
鲍比:不,我是你的第一个男朋友,
Bobby: No, I was the first guy you ever dated.
你有好奇心这一点我很理解,
I can see how you might get a little curious.
嗨,还记得我们第一次约会吗?
Hey, it's amazing you did so well your first time around.
开萝尔:你真能理解我.
Carol: You're so understanding.
鲍比:我摸透了你,要找个漂亮的姑娘很容易,
Bobby: I know temptation.
可就是……
I mean, I see girls every day that I would just love...
开萝尔:鲍比!
Carol: Bobby.
鲍比:对,不说了.
Bobby: I'll shut up.
开萝尔:听着,
Carol: Look, I'm really sorry.
我非常的内疚,你对我比谁都重要,
You mean more to me than anybody and I don't care about your irritating
你暴躁的脾气我一点都不在乎.
habits.
鲍比:我也是这么想你的.愿意的话,
Bobby: Oh, that's just the way I feel about you, too.
你还能去见别人.
You can still see other people if you want.
开萝尔:你也一样.
Carol: Oh, you too.
鲍比:对!
Bobby: Right.
开萝尔:鲍比我们可以这么对看着,也可以吻我.
Carol: Bobby, we can stand here and lie to each other or you can kiss me.
杰森:恩.那我们同意开萝尔和鲍比分手是好事了.
Jason: So, we agree it's a good thing that Carol and Bobby are finished.
麦琪:那当然!00:22:25,000
Maggie: Absolutely.